How old are you?
I'm 22.
22-year-old Swedish guy,
already over 10,000 followers on
socials. You got the world ahead of you.
You got a promising career.
You already got the kudos because
you're Swedish.
How come on content you speak
English and not Svenska?
Because
when I started social media, I was
first thinking about doing in Swedish,
but after
that I wanted to go
broader. So
I started with
English and then
I have just
keep doing it in English
ever since then.
Yeah. You've got what?
10 million Swedish people,
which is not even a tenth of 1%, whereas
10% of the world speak English.
And out of that, out of those 10 million
Swedes,
probably the majority of them speak
English as well, right?
Yeah.
So total addressable market.
Everybody can.
That makes sense.
Yes.
Okay. So
how can I help you?
So, my
biggest problem, I say,
would be
I have
had a lot of problem with
structuring content and
understand how I should
make videos that are...
How can I answer?
So I can understand how I should be
unique,
because right now I believe I take a lot
of
inspiration from others, but
I don't feel that unique. I feel
very much like a robot when I talk.
And
when you talk, it's very authentic and
it feels like you just
make videos.
You are very good at talking
and raw talking, and
I want to-
The first part of that would be,
I've made 10 times as many videos as you
on Insta.
Mm-hmm.
So there's going to be that element.
There's also the fact that,
so firstly, you've done 500 posts,
you've got 16,000 followers.
That's a really good start.
Most people that do 500 posts don't have
16,000
followers. The second,
the fact you're using a second
language to do that already
is incredibly impressive.
So the foundations are really strong.
And to be perfectly honest as well, I
was 24 when I became a personal
trainer,
and if you'd seen my content at 24, it
was terrible.
So you've got a two-year jump on me
already, and you're Swedish, right?
So, you're already going to have
that kind of advantage, that
upper hand. I think
that finding your voice,
it's just going to take a bit of time.
It's also probably going to take a little
bit of maturity.
Also,
this can sound really weird to say to you.
You might not be earning enough yet to
have the confidence.
So it sounds you could be.
I'm not entirely sure.
We'll talk a little bit about
how the business performance is going.
But sometimes you
get yourself to, let's say, 50,
100 clients, and you get your monthly
recurring revenue up a little bit,
and then you start getting results for
your
clients. And sometimes when
that undeniable stack of proof that
you're
communicating from isn't that big,
you can second-guess
yourself. You can be unsure. Also,
this could be the first or
second iteration of making these pieces of
content, and it might take a year or
two for you to have seen the results
and had the people come up to
you and the people say to you, "Oh,
this really helped me." So in
essence, you could just be early for
that feeling to be there.
Before being a personal trainer,
worked in recruitment,
worked in various sales role.
What have you done up until the ages of
22?
So I haven't done much. I
became a personal trainer one year ago,
and
when I was 20, I started with
calisthenics. So
before 20, I
was a very
crazy [chuckles] kid. I was
doing a lot of drugs. I was
partying a lot, drinking, and
then I decided when I became
around 20
that I was going to follow my dreams
because I had a
passion for calisthenics before I was
22. A little 20.
And
then after that,
I decided to become a personal trainer.
So I have only worked
a normal job and-
And this again is great. To be honest,
this just plays into it.
It's a very good story to have.
Do you ever lean into or portray your
journey from cleaning your life up in
content?
Yes. Sometimes. I have actually gone out
with it and
shared a little bit of my story in a few
videos.
Not
a lot of them, but a few
videos I have
It's cool. This is great. And again,
I just want to hone in on
the fact, for your age, to be
making a living from something
and having an online presence
and doing the repetitions,
you've probably got your life together
more than almost everyone your age.
You've probably not even finished.
Your brain hasn't even finished developing
from puberty yet, right?
[chuckles] Until you're 25, you're good.
And then just as your brain develops,
you have three good years,
and then you start
losing your hair. So enjoy it
while you still can.
No, this is great. And what
is it about calisthenics that you
like?
I just fell in love with the
freedom you get with it,
the strength freedom.
Because
I felt it different from only being strong
at the gym to
actually feeling that you
are strong with your
body, that you can
do a muscle up whenever you want,
and you feel like flying up, and
the
balance you can get from doing handstand
and
doing handstand push-ups.
And
I
am a personal trainer now, so I'm at a
private gym,
and
I have seen
my clients get fixed shoulder
injuries just by learning to control their
scapula. And
I have seen
my life change completely.
So I
have a very
love for calisthenics.
I actually love it very much.
It's
not only a passion.
Cool. I'm going to take some notes.
I'm going to send you some content ideas
because often when I do these
calls, people say things very easily, but
they don't potentially know how beneficial
this could be.
So we'll get into your avatar in a second,
but some things you say there,
empowerment,
what could we say? Remedial,
and then another
one.
[sighs] So there's the remedial nature,
there's the
empowerment nature,
there's the strength nature,
and we're going to expand on
these in a second.
Mm-hmm.
And let's put in challenge to
that as well.
So the reason is there's going to be
almost four pillars behind the content you
make about it,
but then also let's appreciate that you
are personal training people,
and I'm sure they come to you,
and actually what they want
is personal training, but they almost are
attracted to the idea of having a twist of
calisthenics with it.
Like when they come to you-
Yeah
... you go, "Hey, John, look,
I'd love to just get you to do muscle ups,
but you
need to be doing lower leg training.
We need to sort out your calories.
We need to do," et cetera.
Because I suppose,
and this could be a video
as well,
every PT has a bias to what they love.
And
it would be
CrossFit PTs do AMRAPs.
Let's say power lifting PTs
do deadlifts.
Hybrid PTs make you run around the car
park.
And as a calisthenics coach,
I make you strong as fuck.
But there's an element to this where you
say you've got to pick your
PT. Oh,
I've just got another idea for a piece of
content here.
Pick your PT like a video game.
So it's a similar kind of version.
You know when you,
[chuckles] depends how much
you want to do this. So you know
when you pick your character at the
beginning and
they're kind of moving a little bit.
You could change your outfits,
so you could do a jujitsu guy, you've got
a gear on with a belt.
Then he changes character,
and you've got your running
shoes, and you're the hybrid PT.
And then calisthenics
is you doing muscle ups,
and then you can kind of have
that as a visual hook, but
then you'd be like, "Look,
I am a normal personal trainer,
but unfortunately when you work
with me,
I am going to get you to do 20 chin-ups
strict.
I am going to teach you how to muscle up,
and I'm going to teach you to handstand
walk because I can't help it. I love this.
As much as I'd love to give you four by
eight back squats and some calories,
my clients,
they just end up on the bar."
And then you can be like, "Well,
the good news is,
it's been great for me, X, Y,
Z." So there's lots of things here,
which I probably
know you've done in content already from
watching it, but the really four important
things here are that we're going to go off
the back of empowerment, remedial,
strength, and challenge.
And now just to expand these a little bit,
and then we'll go into your offer
and everything else from here.
So the reason that I've separated
challenge and empowerment is,
firstly, let me ask,
how many of your clients are female?
Most of them.
Perfect. I had a feeling.
Yeah.
And that's why I had it under empowerment,
right?
Because
as a f--
Here we go. I'm about to mansplain.
As a female,
typically when you go to the gym, you
are lifting lighter
versions of almost everything than men.
However, if you were a woman
and you said to me, "James, I want
to outperform men," I'd probably say,
"Go to calisthenics." Because-
Mm
... men typically
are pretty bad at calisthenics because
their
ego will s-
They'll try doing some calisthenics where
they go, "Fuck this,
I'm going to the bench press," or,
"I'm just going to deadlift-"
Yeah
... with bad technique. Whereas a
woman, you'll say, "Look, this
is a false grip. These are the movements.
This is what you need to do."
And I actually think that,
if I had to train a man or
a woman to become a calisthenics
expert or a hobbyist,
I'd probably rather do it with a woman
because there is an
empowering nature to it.
The first chin-up a man does,
he pretty much just
muscles it with strength
that he's already got.
But for a woman,
it has to be very strategical.
You have to work your way there.
As you're well aware,
you're probably working from horizontal
rows, vertical rows,
eccentrics, banded work, et cetera.
Then when a woman gets that first chin up,
you've taken something that
was once impossible in her life
and made it possible.
And there's an element of gratitude
that they have towards you for that.
I've done it quite a lot of times.
Looking back now, I can't believe how
almost bad some of my advice
was [chuckles]
in the gym.
Because I'm not particularly
that well-gifted at calisthenics.
So the empowerment piece is really cool,
and I think we communicate that to people
in their content by saying-
Mm-hmm
...
[sighs]
how can we start this?
I want to start with a negative hook,
but I just
don't want you to tell women what they're
doing wrong [chuckles] because we'll just
get blasted.
Yeah. [chuckles]
I give men and women different
advice for hitting their first
pull-up.
I still get pull-ups and chin-ups
mixed up with each other. Chin-up is
supinated, pull-up is pronated.
Yes.
When you are teaching a woman,
do you get them to do a chin-up
or a pull-up?
Always start with pull-up.
Cool. There's another
video there. Hold on.
Yeah. [laughs]
Why you always start with a pull-up.
And again,
you might have not realized then,
but you said that with authority.
So-
Mm
... that's a good hook
that you'd be very confident with.
You'd be like, "Guys,
you always start with a pull-up.
Never a chin-up."
[laughs]
Let me explain. And all I need to do
is give you the hooks-
Right
...
because I know you know everything already
from them.
And to be at 16,000 followers,
you're already in a good place. So,
a really good hook there.
I give men and women different advice for
hitting their pull-ups, or this would be
good.
I don't tell men
that much because they don't listen.
[chuckles] But for women-
Yeah. I made a similar video to that
... Perfect. And
that's just the best part. And, okay.
Then there's another version here.
Women shouldn't do pull-ups
for strength
or muscle. They should do it
for empowerment.
Let me explain why.
I think that's another good one.
Yeah.
I know you've got your school community.
We'll get onto that in a second.
Mm-hmm.
Have you done many videos?
I see you've done some videos with
clients.
Have you ever-
Yes
... recorded a session? Oh yeah,
I can see, and they perform
really well.
Mum picks up pull-up-
Yeah. That's my mom
... form just the same. Perfect. This
is unreal.
That's the one
like format I have actually found that
makes me a little bit more unique,
if I say so,
because I do a lot of videos with my
family.
Amazing.
And they perform very well.
[inhales] But there's some really good
things here.
I'm just going to do this. God,
the [chuckles] ideas come to me.
Okay. So I'm making like a family
area on the document.
Okay.
As a PT,
the hardest type of person
to train
isn't lazy people,
it's family. [chuckles] It's family.
Because
I'm not a coach to my mum,
I'm her son,
and I'm supposed to listen to
what she says,
not the other way around.
Yes.
So you might have done this before.
Then the family one,
I make videos with my mum,
not like that, you dirty pervert.
I got my mum to do a
muscle up in three months doing these
three things. [chuckles]
We won't go down the incest-
Don't [laughs]
... path too much.
Yeah. We'll skip that one.
How old's your mum?
50 now.
Okay, cool. 59 or 50?
50.
Okay, cool.
Quite old.
I was going to say,
I found a random old lady,
but we'll say I found a random lady
and taught her to muscle up in
two months. And then I want like a clip.
I'm his mum, by the way. I'm not random.
So like, for instance, we
are doing some stuff
on TikTok at the moment for the focus
pouches.
Have you tried these yet?
I'll send you some, if not.
No, actually I've not. I-
But you're going to love your snus.
Yeah, I know. We are-
So then-
We are-
They're not going to hit you
that hard like compared.
And you guys, you
were years ahead of everyone else.
I remember being in Bali, and like-
Mm
... I won't incriminate myself,
but I probably had a couple too many
shandies, and
I offered to give a Swedish girl a lift
home.
This is when I was much, much younger
and a single man, and it was on the
claim that I drove slow, we wore helmets,
and that I took a snus,
and she was like, "I need you sharp.
I need you focused." I felt so sick.
I nearly crashed the moped because-
Yeah. [chuckles] Yeah
... she must have put like a 10
or 15 milligram in.
[laughs] That's crazy. People
that have never tried it
before, they are not ready for a-
No
... strong snus.
Okay. So, what I was saying there was,
so there's one guy who's our top
affiliate.
I want to send him videos to put into his
TikToks, even if it's just
very
quick little snippets. So for instance-
I want him to say, "You might
have seen these before.
They're made by Chris Williamson
and James Smith, the
creator who's going bald." Then I want to
send him a video going, "I'm not going
that bald." But that video,
he can then put in content and go,
"Shut up, James."
And then because there's a little scene
change, so you could be shooting
from afar, "I found a random woman."
Or you could say,
"I found a random old woman. All right,
she's only 50, and I taught her
how to do a muscle-up in three months."
Then she does the muscle-up, and then it's
a clip of her going, "Random,
I'm your mother." And then it goes
back to it, and you're like, whatever.
So there's some fun you can have with
that as well-
Yeah
... where we-
...
kind of film it in a way where you make
digs, and it could be
another family member.
I found a homeless old man asking for
money and got
him strong.
And then your dad could be like,
"Homeless?
You live at home with us.
I'm your dad." And for people-
[laughs] Yeah
... for people out there,
I remember I went around a friend's house,
and I still remember this to this day.
His dad was gardening.
I'd never met his dad before,
and as he walks to the
front door, he shouts, "No,
I haven't got any money.
Go away," and walks in the house.
And I was like, "Who's that?" He said,
"Ask my
dad." Just randomly, and it cracked me up.
I couldn't believe he'd do it-
Okay [laughs]
... just to get a laugh out of me.
And yeah,
so even-
That's a good idea
... if you're going to use your family,
that could be a really funny one.
And then you could just make up random
lies.
I
welcomed this woman to come live with me
till I got her strong.
I already live with her.
Yeah [laughs]
That's my son or whatever it is.
So the family side there is,
if I can get this random lady strong,
I can help
anyone. Here's how to do it.
And she's like,
"Stop calling me a random lady.
I gave birth to you."
Another thing I was thinking of would
be if you were to ever get your mom
or someone
else to potentially cuss you in Swedish,
and then you could even say to
the camera, "Oh,
she's just calling me silly."
But really it's
like a
rude thing in Swedish
or something that's kind of offensive,
because then your
Swedish audience will be like, "Oh,
it's like an inside joke.
Oh, she's just saying
that I'm good at my job."
So,
that'd be a good way to Trojan horse it.
Because down
in
where I live, close to Denmark, we
have this special
dialect where
the other part of Sweden, they
know
us for our dialect, and it's a bit weird,
weirder than [chuckles] the other part of
Sweden.
So that can be a good one, actually.
Yeah. You can-
Could be very good
...
say whatever you want because you're
talking to an English audience.
So,
those things, I think, would be-
Mm
... a beginning to have some fun with it.
Now,
okay, so we looked at empowerment. So
that was a really good start.
The remedial side of things,
this is where we're probably going to go
with more curiosity hook.
So dead hangs.
So let's think about dead hangs,
for example.
If you had to set
a standard,
how long should someone be able to do a
dead hang for?
Before they-
Just in general
... start pull-up or only-
Just to be a good human-
In general-
Good human being
...
you should at least for,
I would say, 90 seconds.
Wow, okay, cool. All right, sweet.
So if you can't dead hang for 90
seconds,
you've got your priorities wrong in life.
Or you could do a
dead hang challenge.
Could be a whiteboard.
Under 30 seconds-
Mm
... wow,
30 to 60,
you
devolved too far
from the ape. [chuckles] 90 seconds,
okay, I will look you in the eyes.
Obviously,
90 seconds plus,
good.
But you can have some fun with it.
But you could
put a serious-
Yeah
... tone on it and be like, "Guys, this
is serious.
This is one of the main things that's
important.
How long can you dead hang for?" Another
thing should be
why do dead hangs fix shoulder
issues?
And you could even just say things like,
"I don't know, but this is why I
get my clients to do them."
[chuckles]
It's crazy, actually, because one of my
greatest video performing is when I teach
out how to do the scapula properly, and
that's a exercise a lot of people skip,
but I have
actually found a way where you can
use the scapula to actually be able to do
your first pull-up.
So-
Scapula
... I don't know if you saw that video.
Yeah, scapula pull-ups. I don't know
if you saw that video,
but
on
my Instagram, I can-
And do you know what?
It's going to be one of those things where
when those videos
do really well,
you've just got to keep making it. So-
Mm
...
here's something to consider just on a
little tangent.
The fact that you've said
that you think that the
average amount of time someone should be
able to hang from a bar is 90
seconds,
you are
potentially
Overestimating the average human,
and this isn't a bad thing.
This is the thing I need to remind you.
Mm.
I would say the average person can do
between 15 and 20
seconds,
and that's being generous.
I would say one of the reasons most people
can't do
that many chin-ups
is because of the ability of hanging onto
the bar.
Right, here you go.
Mm.
I wonder if there's another video in this.
If you had to hold on
for dear life,
you'd probably die in under 20 seconds.
So, imagine green screening
someone hanging onto a helicopter,
or actually even I would love to see you
react to film
of someone hanging on a helicopter
or something where someone does that.
Definitely.
Yeah. You could just be like,
"In this film,
Captain America held on to a helicopter
for one minute and 20 seconds.
How difficult is that?"
And then you could be
like-
Mm
...
"I've taken five of my clients to see
whether or not they could
survive in that film." And then
if they let go before that period of
time, you just say to them, "You're dead.
You're dead." Or you could get people in
the gym and go-
[laughs]
... "Hey,
I'm trying to see how long people can hold
onto the chin-up bar."
Someone does 20 seconds,
you can then turn to them and be like-
Mm
... "Really? Really?"
And then towards the end of the video,
you're then like,
"Look,
here are some of the biggest mistakes
that people are making." But let's
continue with the dead hang thing here is,
here's some
free advice-
Mm. Oh, good
... for bad shoulders.
So, the free advice for bad shoulders.
Okay.
Say I say to you, "Oh,
I've got really tight pecs,
my shoulder health isn't feeling great,
I've got a few niggles.
How wide should I have my hands on the
bar?"
If you only dead hang?
Yeah.
If you only do a dead hang, okay.
I should say
only shoulder-width.
Why?
Like when you're doing a muscle-up,
because
it's unnecessary to have them wider
because when you have them closer to you,
you can just
relax with your shoulders a bit more.
This is real.
Instead of having them out here,
because out here
you need to activate your lats more.
Okay.
How wide should your hands be depends on
do you need your
lats?
For a dead hang, no.
For a muscle-up, yes.
We haven't even got into fucking
muscle-ups yet.
So, the dead hang, I think is-
Mm
...
they say the reason you speak English in
content is because you want a total
addressable market, right?
Your dead hang is your total addressable
market.
Your dead hang is every single person
should
know that hanging from a bar
is good for their health.
Say I'm here and I'm like, "Look,
my shoulders are all messed up from
jujitsu.
I want to start dead hanging."
Do you have a protocol
or a program I could follow?
No.
Or I don't have a ready to go.
Okay.
But I have in mind [chuckles] what you can
do.
Dead hang protocol.
I think we can have some fun with this-
Mm-hmm
... where your squeeze page can say,
"Don't die."
You could be hanging from a helicopter,
you never know.
[laughs]
You could slip off a roof, right?
And there's you hanging one-armed
and you're
like-
Okay. [laughs]
You're like, "Don't die before your time.
Do my dead hang protocol."
[laughs] Okay.
You could slip getting snow off the roof
in Sweden,
and as long as you get one hand to the
gutter, you could hang there for a few
minutes, call for help,
get your neighbor's ladder, and be like,
"Look, if you
can't dead hang for a minute, you'll die,
and you can just
have some fun. Download this."
And then you can also say something
like,
"I've saved 22 lives with my dead hang
program." And then towards the end,
you can
be like, "Oh, that's maybe not true,
but it could be 22 people,
you never know."
Or again, in this dead hang protocol,
really what we're doing
is we're trying to create an asset
that could be beneficial
to people,
which I think it could because me going
downstairs and jumping on the
bar,
I'll do it for three days,
and then I'll go, "Cool."
And then that's it,
because I know because I still
don't do that much dead hang from the bar,
even though I know how good it is for
me. Would you tell me to tape my bar?
[laughs]
Use chalk-
Why?
... should I say?
That's the best because you get a
better grip, and if you have sweaty hands,
it's
perfect.
Okay.
Right. Chalk, better than tape.
So that, again, is another video.
Mm.
You could even set your hook could be
like,
"CrossFitters
are real weird, man.
Why do they love
using tape so much?"
And again,
you can just have a little poke at the
bear.
So, the dead hang protocol, I think,
is really good for you
because
deep down, if I was to say to you,
16,000 people in your audience,
how many do you think could dead hang for
over a minute?
Oof.
Maybe more than 50%.
I'm not sure. I'm not sure.
No. Well,
even then you got 8,000 people to download
the program.
So,
there's a lot,
and given the wider audience,
I'm telling you
now, I reckon less than 5% of the world
can dead hang for more than a minute.
Now, your program, your protocol,
it could work them towards like a
three-minute dead hang.
Mm-hmm.
And in that, some people listening
might be like, "Why
is James getting so excited about getting
people to hang from
a bar?" Because we know it's more than
that.
They're going to progress in this.
They're going to build strength.
They're going to see their times go up
and up and up.
Day 15,
they're going to jump off the bar and go,
"Wow, two minutes
was three times easier than what 30
seconds used to be." Then
every day they progress and do better.
Mm-hmm.
They
might do a max hold on the Thursday,
then it might be
like five by 10 seconds with a weight on
the Friday.
Then it might be whatever,
you're going to be programming this.
Then by the time they finish,
they've got a taste of your programming,
your
methodology, your execution,
and they're going to have what results
look like,
so that if they did want to buy your
program or your product
or whatever it was, we
could
follow up really well. So,
three weeks after they start the program,
"Hey, how are you getting on?
This is one of my free resources.
If you're interested to learn how to
muscle up,
if you're looking for one-to-one coaching
or whatever." We could just have
something that's crushing in the
background.
And, again,
I think the people would nibble on that.
Mistakes people make. If I
was trying to dead hang for three minutes,
would I need a false grip?
No.
Why?
Because, the false grip will just make it
harder for you to hold onto the bar.
Cool. It's another reel.
Yeah.
What is the false grip?
The false grip is
when you have your knuckles
pointed upwards to the sky.
What is it? What is it?
It's-
What's the purpose?
Two types of false grip.
That looks a bit weird.
Why would I lift my body with a weird
wrist
like that?
[chuckles] Because it's easier
if you do a muscle up,
because if I hold onto the bar like this,
I can't go over with my wrist.
It takes stops.
But if I rotate my wrist a little bit,
it will be much easier for me to get
over the bar.
Another piece of content.
I'm sure you've done this before,
but so the remedial
side-
[chuckles]
... of things,
what about a one-arm dead hang?
I've seen this in your content.
Oh.
Should people be able to do a one-arm dead
hang?
Yeah, I...
No, they sh-
or yes,
I believe you should be able to do it, but
if you're a beginner,
you would probably not be able to do it.
But it's good to be able to do it.
Cool. So, again,
we could do the whiteboard thing again,
10-second one-arm dead hang,
cool.
Mm-hmm.
20 seconds plus, you're a freak. And
if you've got 30 seconds plus,
you're on steroids. Again, you could
have some fun with that.
[chuckles]
And again, just talk me through it.
And now, okay,
just before we get into strength,
we're going to get into the muscle
up.
I want to reiterate
the questions I'm asking you,
whatever amount of people you think know
this already, it is so much less.
There are millions-
Mm-hmm
... in some respects,
I know you're probably not
over-complicating it already.
I want you to make sure
that your content is accessible to
everyone.
If you're going to speak English,
because there's fucking-
Mm
... 80 million people
that speak English or whatever.
No, 800 million. Sorry.
Mm-hmm.
Then the same way I need you to talk about
things, because think about the amount
of people that have access to a chin-up
bar.
Do you know how many people don't even
know what calisthenics is?
Yeah, I know. I have realized
that actually, because every
time I've
started with a hook where I say
calisthenics,
it has performed
not good at all.
So,
yeah. That is something I have actually
thought a lot about, to not
name calisthenics.
When you start every reel,
I want you to appreciate the average
person
doesn't know what calisthenics is.
The average person doesn't know what the
fuck a false grips is.
The average person doesn't even know what
chalk does.
Mm.
They don't even realize
that chalk creates friction-
Yeah
...
or that chalk absorbs moisture from the
sweat. They don't know.
The average person-
Mm
...
has probably got 1.2 chin-ups in the tank.
1.2. That's being generous, because only
17% of people in the UK-
Mm
... have got a gym membership. So,
in the nicest way
possible,
the best bit of advice is, and this
is going to sound horrible, speak as if
you've got an audience of people with CTE.
Like they're all slightly mentally
handicapped.
Because when you speak to those people,
there's that guy, Gilliam
Fitness,
who talks to his audience like they've got
CTE.
He's doing it as a joke,
but the videos perform well because people
actually
understand him.
So many people out there,
especially in the calisthenics world,
they try and
overcomplicate things to sound smart.
And even some of the stuff here,
I think it is, why should you
learn to do a chin-up?
And you could be like, "So you don't die.
Let me explain." There could be an
element, you fall off the roof.
You could
be in a car chase,
and you could fall out the door,
and you need to hold onto it or
whatever it is. Have some fun with it,
because everyone, again,
[chuckles] I don't know
if you've ever done this.
I think it was the last "Mission
Impossible" where he has to go down to the
submarine to get something.
I tried holding my breath for the whole
time he did
it in the cinema, and I was like,
"Nah." No one's holding their breath
for that long. In a film, I'm the guy
that holds the breath, but the people out
there are going to be thinking, like,
"How do these people hold on for so long?"
Again, another video idea could be
how long can
you hold yourself on the bar?
And then, so imagine
if you said to someone,
"All right,
how long can you hold yourself on the
bar?" They might do
45 seconds.
Then you give them a full recovery,
and you get out a 100 euro
note. You go, "If you beat it,
I'll give you 100 euros." And then they're
hanging on. Then the next time,
they do over 45 seconds,
and you could be like,
people are financially incentivized to be
stronger.
Another thing that could be really good,
this is going to be
as you level up a little bit
[inhales] , hold on.
Oh, again,
people in the street literally do
competitions where
they go, "Hold on for one minute,
win 1,000 euros."
You said 90 seconds-
Yeah, I know
... is good.
60 seconds, you win 1,000 euros.
And I know they use the rotation.
[chuckles] Yeah.
They use the rotation shit.
Um-
Because I think I can
hold
on to, without changing my grip,
I can probably hold
on for three minutes.
I've got a sick video for you here.
All right, okay.
So you're going to take a screenshot of
the guys in the street doing this.
You're going to react,
and you're going to go,
"I'm going to teach you how to win
that 1,000 euros next time you see one of
these.
My name's Emil.
I'm an expert at anything
that includes hanging from a bar.
Let me teach you five principles
that you can implement,
so the next time you
see these scoundrels in the street,
you're going to win 1,000 euros." So then
your hook is,
I'm going to help you make money.
The next time you see one of these,
you're going to win because of what I'm
going to teach you.
You could even say like-
Okay.
... These guys
hate me so much, I had to change my name.
I had to change my address.
They found this video of me teaching
people calisthenics, and they've come
after me.
They've been sending me death threats.
Stop teaching people how to be so good on
the
bar.
All right. That's a good one.
[chuckles] Mate, you sound like, mate,
I've got a massive fucking document for
you
here, I tell you that.
[chuckles] Yeah.
Then, of course, we've got first,
muscle up.
But then why? And it would be, again,
empowerment,
because your boyfriend can't.
So,
here we can say, men hate women-
Ooh
... who can muscle up
because men can't do them.
[inhales] I want to teach you to muscle
up,
to
emasculinate
your boyfriend.
Your boy-
boyfriends hate it [chuckles] when I teach
this. This is the muscle
up, and
women
that do them
often have their boyfriends leave them.
[laughs] And again,
you can joke with this.
No one's going to fact-check you and say,
"Where was the breakups?" Because
we're all about stopping people's
attention.
You win them over, but the reason
that the beginning of it is unserious
and fun
is so that once you've done that,
you've got them, and you're like, then you
go into coach mode.
Because coaches all have
the coach acumen. What they don't have
is the ability to stop someone in their
tracks and almost have some fun with it as
well.
I was joking the other day that I
was doing some ads for the Zyns.
I've started with some hooks going,
my neighbor's cat died by eating a
Zyn or a nicotine pouch. I
was like, "Rest in peace, Socksy."
Switch over to nicotine pouches.
Save the cats.
It's not true,
but someone's going to be like,
they know it's not true-
Oh, no
... but it's just fucking whatever.
Yeah. [chuckles]
You fact-check me. So,
by saying this, by saying to women,
"Oh, your boyfriend's going to hate this.
But here's what I would do to do a muscle
up."
And you could even draw the story out.
You're going to come home.
Your boyfriend's going to ask what you got
up to today, and you're going to have to
tell him, "Babe,
I learned to muscle up."
And he's going to be like,
"You learned to what? It's okay
that you can't do this.
It's okay that you're too weak,
but I'm not.
I'm strong." And we can storyboard it
or whatever like-
Yeah, that's a good...
Um-
Yes.
[chuckles]
Are toes to bar part of calisthenics?
They are, aren't they?
What?
Toes to bar?
Toes to bar, yes. Toes to bar is a
combination between CrossFit
and calisthenics, but calisthenic is a
stricter version of
CrossFit.
Okay, so toes to bar.
Benefits,
the core actually flexes.
We've got lots of content where most
people train their hip
flexors.
So have you done any content,
hip flexor versus
actual core?
No.
So let's say-
If you do a hanging leg raise
and your legs go to 90 degrees-
Mm
... it's really a hip flexor exercise.
Mm-hmm.
But if you go toes to bar-
Yeah
...
you're actually starting to contract the
abdominals.
The abdominals have to shorten.
Whereas when you're doing a leg raise up
to 90 degrees-
Yeah
...
the abdominal is really isometrically
supporting the pelvis going into
hip flexion with the hip flexors.
So I want you to come out and educate
people, this is not a core exercise,
it's mostly hip flexors.
To make it a core exercise,
I want your toes to come all
the way to the bar. Now, this
is a calisthenics movement. Here
are some tips.
One, grip strength, two, the initiation,
three, the contraction.
The fact that you could add some kipping
motion, good for CrossFit.
So the best jujitsu coach in the world,
the only core exercise he gets athletes to
do in jujitsu is toes to
bar, strict. Because in jujitsu,
we have to
close our knee, basically,
we have to get a really strong
knee-to-elbow connection to prevent
someone passing the guard.
Have you ever trained jujitsu?
A little bit, yeah.
So if someone's got-
Little bit
... really good flexion and really good
abdominal strength-
Mm-hmm
...
it becomes incredibly difficult to pancake
them out, which you would need to do
to pass their guard.
So there's another rule there.
Yeah.
If you practice jujitsu,
you should be able to do 10 strict toes to
bar.
Here are the criteria
that you need to get.
Again-
Mm-hmm
... sit-ups are crap.
Do toes to bar instead, this is why.
Yeah.
The best core exercise in the world also
is fantastic for your shoulders
and your forearms. Let me show you why.
Mm.
Why just train your abs
when you could do a full body movement?
This is why.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Let's go back to this document for a
second.
So yeah, the toes to bar,
you've got so many benefits there as well.
And again, people out there,
I want you to think,
nine out of 10 people that watch
these videos are never going to do
anything with you,
but one day they're going to
be like, "Bro,
been watching your content for a few
years.
I've now got a chin-up bar in my back
garden and I'm on it every day."
I sometimes even dream of putting a
chin-up bar-
Yeah
... on my balcony at home
and just doing calisthenics.
But then I end up just doing, I just do
bench press at the gym. Also,
here's one for you.
My shoulders are okay,
but all my chin-up work I do,
I just go neutral grip.
And I think it's because it's easier for
me.
If you could sell me into-
Yeah, it is
...
if you could sell me into doing some
pronated, I can't do
supinated, my elbow would explode.
I've got no supination.
If I supinate my right hand-
Yeah
...
I get a crunch on the inside of my elbow,
like a loud crunch.
There's something wrong there.
But the thing is, mate, I'm 37,
I'll die with that elbow issue.
And I'm okay-
Yeah
... with that. That's okay. But
if you were trying to get me to do some
pronated-
Yeah
... when I do pronated work,
everything just gets a bit ugly.
Because, I suppose,
what's it called where you
like tense your core
and point your toes in front of you?
Yeah. I don't know the name in
English,
but when you point your toes to the sky.
So
you don't want to be a gymnast
and point your toes down.
Okay.
You want to point your toes up,
because that will tighten a
little bit your hamstring, actually.
So you will not bend your knees.
But,
for the neutral grip, it's easier because
most often you use more
of your arms when you hold closer
than wider. Because when you hold
wider, you can actually activate your lats
a little bit easier. But
most often, people
are stronger in their arms than their lats
because they don't know how to activate
their lats.
So if I would have guessed,
your pull-ups will
probably look, when you go down,
you stop right
here.
Yeah.
And then you go up again.
You don't go all the way down.
Mm-hmm.
It's because you don't know how to
activate your lats-
Yeah
... correctly.
Yeah.
And that's probably why your shoulders-
But they don't hurt.
They just don't feel very nice.
One day I'll do a business trip to Sweden.
You can train me for all of this.
Okay.
And also the thing is now-
Yeah
... functionally, I
don't mind narrow grip chin-ups because
all I use that strength for is guillotines
anyway. So once I've got someone's head,
all I've got to do is make a-
Mm
... full-grown man tap.
That's all I've got to do.
You've just reminded me there,
something I would love-
Yeah
... something I'd love for you to do.
You know when you're thinking,
sometimes you're like, what's the word?
When you're in content, let's say you're,
oh, if you can't do a
30-second dead hang,
what do we say in Swedish?
You're weak as piss. Or be like-
[laughing] Yeah
... you should take a second.
Yeah.
This is where your personality can come
out.
You should be like, "If you can't do-
Mm
...
a one-minute dead hang," how do we say
this in Swedish?
"Your parents should be ashamed."
And then move on to something else.
And kind of script it what you would put
in, because people are going to be waiting
for a Swedish change,
but you could even just lie.
You could say a Swedish word.
What's the Swedish word for weak?
Svag.
What is it? Sval?
Svag. So you could be like-
S-V-A-G
So again, you could be like,
if you don't even have one minute, in
Swedish we call this [in Swedish] svag,
but
in English we could call this
weaker than your sister, or
never been to the gym,
or
you have arms of a snowman.
Something like that.
Just something funny
and [chuckles] you just have some fun with
it.
Okay.
So we've got some toes to bar stuff.
You know what to do on the first muscle
ups.
I tell you who does very well with this.
Do you know Harriet Roberts?
Harriet Roberts? No.
I'll share my screen.
So Harriet Roberts is an Aussie.
She's a gymnastics skills coach. Look,
I'm not
going to take credit for everything here,
but I can't remember how I first got in
touch with Harriet Roberts, but I
messaged her because she'd gone to the
CrossFit
Games as a female athlete,
and I'd followed her for a
year, and she hadn't sold me anything.
And I was like:
"You have so many skills in your head."
But she
was just too scared to post about it.
But
her stuff is amazing. It's actually sick.
She's got Harriet Roberts as the handle as
well.
But can you see my screen, yeah?
Yes.
So this one, 73,000
likes,
and she's just filming from a
side view.
She's going through different motions,
hollow swings,
Supermans.
We look to this one here,
handstand challenge,
so that's quite interesting with the
broomstick
there.
I've never seen this one before.
I've liked it before,
so I must've watched it.
110,000 likes.
So what I'd do is I'd come onto her page
and look at stuff.
Also, if you don't want to plagiarize it,
you could take a picture of
this and react to it and give her credit.
Mm-hmm.
Look at this, right? So this
is over a year old, and
people are still commenting on it seven
weeks ago, eight weeks ago, three weeks
ago. So this video
is going to be growing her account
ongoing.
Then-
Wow
... stuck at the bottom of your ring dip,
start here.
So Harriet here has done years of stuff,
so you don't have to.
Yeah.
And
you could just come here, and again,
there are going to be
people that want to learn this from her,
and there are going to be some
people that would prefer to learn this
from you.
There's nothing inherently wrong with
taking inspiration from
her because I hope that she
is doing the same thing, and that she
is-
Mm
...
looking at other creators in this world
and doing the same thing.
So
yeah, she's going to be someone
that you're going to do a bit of homework
on.
I can imagine-
Yes
... the same way that you--
Think of it this way.
Harriet should be a pretty big inspiration
to you as a content
creator in this space,
but you never even knew she existed.
But in the same way,
you can be a massive inspiration to a lot
of people that don't know you exist.
But
the more that you build your own profile
in calisthenics, it's better for her, it's
better for you, it's better for everyone.
So again-
Mm
...
if another brand comes out tomorrow
and they're doing focus
pouches,
or another brand comes out tomorrow
and does a productivity drink,
you might think that that annoys me,
but actually,
I'm quite happy for people to be
talking about this because that
is going to, the rising
tide lifts all boats.
The more people talk about calisthenics,
the better business
is going to be for you.
So she's going to be a really important
and pivotal
person to watch her content.
She's absolutely killing it.
She's doing well.
I need to check in with her soon.
Yeah. I will
check her out after this call.
Yes.
Because it says gymnast
skill coach, but she's doing CrossFit.
Yeah.
But you can't sell-
Yeah
... CrossFit,
so she became a gymnast skills coach.
Because also,
the total addressable market of
CrossFitters that need help versus the
amount of
people that just want to get good at
muscle ups and handstands
and ring dips and
all that.
So it could even be worth--
You could even take calisthenics out of
your profile
and just say, "I help people."
Yeah.
"I help people move their body."
I
actually heard about that yesterday.
It was something similar to
CrossFitters don't make money,
and I was
very confused.
Because
gymnasts, if I'm not wrong, they make more
money than CrossFitters do.
Yeah. It wouldn't surprise me.
Just from athletes.
So Harriet won't mind me
sharing this.
So I messaged her probably in like
2020, 2021, and I pretty much said
to her, "You're such a good athlete.
You should be making a lot of money." I
don't think she was making a lot of money
at the time. And I said to her,
"Selfishly, you shouldn't want to make
money as an entrepreneur.
You should want to make money as an
athlete." I said, "If
you're going to go compete at the World
Games, you should be flying there business
class because you're a fucking athlete.
You should be sleeping on that flight-
Mm
... not sitting upright." So I said,
"Your selfish endeavors should be
To make as much money as you can so
that you
can be the best athlete possible.
So there's all of
these components where CrossFitters
are flying to the games in economy
five days out, and then again,
the hotel they stay in, how close they
are to the venue, the quality
of the bed at the hotel,
all these things are considerations.
It's going to sound real wanky to say
this, but I've got a
lot of travel in the next few weeks.
I'm going to Richard Branson's island next
week, and
I upgraded my flights to first class so I
can have a better sleep, because
I'm going to be so tired on that trip.
I really want to get writing my next book
as well.
So I've not upgraded to first for any
other reason than I want to be
more comfortable sleeping because
if my sleep goes from six hours to 10
hours,
that benefits me as a business person
because I can be more productive.
So
maybe that is just a cope to upgrade my
flight.
But the same way that
most of these CrossFitters,
if they really cared about CrossFit,
they would become
good business people.
But that's another tangent altogether.
Right.
So,
we got the challenge side of things as
well.
I think we've covered a lot-
That's exactly what I want to do with-
Go on.
Yeah, no, I was just saying that's
exactly what I want to do with the
calisthenics, too, because
I compete also. So
that's also a reason why-
What does competing in calisthenics look
like?
So, it's called endurance calisthenics,
and that's when you do
a round with different
numbers of different exercises. For
example, you can do
20 muscle ups, 40 pull-ups,
80 dips, and 100 push-ups, and then you
are supposed to do that as
fast as possible and the one that
does it the fastest, they win.
And then you compete
like a 1v1 match
to compete beside
each other. So it's-
Because-
... it's a pretty intense game, and-
One of the hardest
rounds at CrossFit is Murph, and Murph
is mostly calisthenics, is it not?
Like it's-
Yeah
... chin-ups, squats-
... press-ups. All right. So-
Yep. That's exactly what there
is calisthenics.
Cool. All right.
And I want you to also document that.
So when things go well or wrong at comp,
you pretty much are just saying to
yourself, "This went
well,
this is what didn't go well," et cetera.
I'm just going to share with you this
document just before I forget.
[chuckles]
All right.
I'm going to put it in the chat here.
Are you on mobile or you're on your
laptop?
Laptop.
Cool. So there's a little chat feature,
should pop up in a second. If not,
I can email that to you afterwards.
So there's a load of content ideas,
but let's have a look at your offer.
So I think that
I almost want you to create
that lead magnet,
but not as a lead magnet.
When you create the dead hang system
or whatever it is that you're going to do,
I want you to genuinely create something
that's going to help thousands of people
for free, and almost as
if come the end of it,
you're like, "Cool, I'm doing
this just to help people." Because I
genuinely think you can get thousands and
thousands of people on it,
and then a certain percentage of them
are just going to
hire you because they trust you
and they like you.
And I know that sounds like crazy things
to say.
Some of the reason,
so I work with thousands of businesses
like yours every year,
and as much as I would love to say it's
because
I'm skilled and experienced,
I would also like to think it's probably
just because they go, "Look,
I'm going to spend $1,000 with someone,
might as well be someone
that I like." Might as well.
And I think we don't give people enough
credit for that.
If you make people laugh,
the content with your mom as well.
Sean Casey, do you follow him?
Sure. Yeah. Yes.
The boring guy. No, I'm joking. But he-
I do
...
he puts his mom in content all the time.
Just bought his mom a Porsche,
like retired his mom a few years ago.
Yeah.
And people love it because
when people look at that content,
they're going to
be thinking about the relationship they
have with their son, and they're going to
see you as like their little son.
Your career arc over the next
10 years will be,
for the next eight years,
women will love you.
But then as you get a little bit older,
you'll get a bit more of a
masculine audience,
and some of the women will lose
that connection because you'll
lose your youth and you'll get a little
bit older.
They won't see you as a son anymore.
It's kind of weird, like my audience
was 80% women, and then it's slowly
become 50/50.
But yeah,
so there's the content side of things.
Now,
how many clients do you have in the gym?
So right now I have
around 10 to 15.
I
offer five weeks, and then I offer one,
two, or
three times a week for those five weeks.
Cool.
So it's three different-
You're in a great position for your age as
well, and you've probably got a lot of
time as well to do some content in your
spare time.
So I would say, that's good.
As you start to grow the onsite stuff
and get
even more traction, fuck me,
16,000 followers in your first year.
You're going to be flying soon.
I genuinely believe that.
I would probably say 20 hours
is probably going to be your sweet spot,
otherwise
you might get bogged down in it.
Now, the one thing that I'm not
The biggest fan on,
and you can tell me otherwise.
Why did you pick Skool as a platform?
I don't know. I have heard
you talk about it, and
I was already on Skool at that time.
I
actually don't know any other platforms
where I can use,
where I can pay, where
someone
needs to pay for the community.
Because my thinking was get them into the
community to
then try to
get them into the high ticket,
my one-v-one offer.
How much is your one-v-one?
So my one-v-one is monthly
249.
Cool. $249 US?
Yes.
Cool. See, that to me is a nice amount.
The issue is,
I'll share it on my screen as well so
people can
see.
Can you see my screen?
Yes.
So I get here.
I don't really see much branding.
I don't know what Twist the Rules means.
And
first of all, I see three members,
so I think it's shit
because only three people do it.
I also then see $29 a month,
and I think it's shit because it's
$29 a month.
I know in your head you probably think,
I'll get
1,000 people on this,
I get 100 on my one-to-one,
but ultimately, if
the link in your bio takes me to something
that I perceive
as shit,
that's a problem. Why
is your name Lex Twister?
That was just
because...
Yeah, it's a long story.
It's a long story, but it has been my name
ever since day one.
So it's a long story.
Are you against changing your name to Emil
Krantz?
No, I'm not against it. I would do it.
I
can do it.
The only thing is, right-
It's just-
Let's say
a year from today,
you're at 150,000 followers.
You're doing events around Sweden
and in the
UK and in Norway.
When you get asked to do a talk somewhere
or you get your
first booking-
Mm-hmm
... when they've got the microphone,
do you want them to call you Lex Twister?
No. I think
the reason why I put Lex Twister
is mostly because
I just wanted that identity shift.
I think
that's probably
the biggest reason why I changed to Lex
Twister.
But I
can change to Emil Krantz.
I think-
It's not something I-
I think
Alex Hormozi, Steven Bartlett,
Chris Williamson,
Jimmy Carr,
whoever it is,
they are themselves.
I
don't think this is,
unless you're a pro wrestler
I don't know about.
Mm.
I think that should be your name.
I think if I'm going to pay you $250 a
month-
Mm
... I want to pay Emil, not Lex Twister.
Now, love the rest of it.
One thing I don't like
is these promotions here. So ESN,
are these
supplements?
Yeah. ESN is supplement and GORNATION
is equipment.
Do they pay you a retainer every month?
So ESN,
I get €300
every month to
buy from them.
And GORNATION,
I just got GORNATION
to give me €500 of
equipment for a
three-month contract.
As part of your contract,
do they have to be the top of your bio?
Not top of the bio. You can have something
above.
I would rather your first call to action
is something better.
So the first thing that I see there
should be,
because I want you to grow your business
before theirs.
I'm happy for them to be here.
Yeah.
And if they don't like it-
Mm
... they can fuck off. Right. Fair enough.
$500 a month, $300 a month.
Yeah.
Sounds lovely.
But two clients would also do that.
Mm.
And the two clients will be with you
and help you-
Yeah
... and referrals and help you. So
if they're paying you
and paying the bills,
cool. I'm all right with that.
So you got two call to actions here.
"DM me change for a free 14-day
calisthenics mastery."
I don't know what calisthenics mastery is,
for a start.
So that has to change. Also-
Yeah
... it just looks a little bit botty.
Like
change, DM me the word change.
If you want to change,
if you're looking to make the
most out of your life,
say fuck yeah. Three, two, one, fuck yeah.
It's
a bit corny. You know what I mean?
And then here,
master the basics and see the changes,
and you send me to a Skool account.
I'm like, come on, brother.
So do you know what I'd much
rather
If you want to know your first muscle-up,
send me a message. Or-
Mm-hmm
... even actually,
I think we just have a lead to a lead
magnet.
We could even say free resources or-
Because
...
get stronger, have a link tree,
deadhang guide,
muscle-up starter kit,
and let's name them real simple,
like how to hit your first muscle-up,
how to hit your first tension ups.
Let's just make it impossibly easy for
people to
navigate that. This at the moment
is just a bit naff.
It's just a bit like, cool.
Yeah.
That's the bit I want to change.
Because, right.
Mm.
Sorry, do you have any data-
So right now I have-
Go on.
[chuckles]
Do you have any data of how many people
get to this page and just fucking leave?
Yeah. Probably a lot of people.
Yeah, and that's the problem.
So they come here, they go, "Oh,
I look shit." They
fuck off. You get no data from them.
You get none of their emails. All right.
So if I DM you the word change, boom.
Let's go.
Really happy to finally understand the
benefits of calisthenics.
Want to start now. Want to check out...
Where's my guide, brother?
I just DMed you that,
and you haven't even sent it to me.
And your follow-up, want to check out,
yeah, obviously,
where's my fucking guide?
You looking at this on your phone as well?
Why have you got-
Well, you should get a button to click.
See, I'm not enjoying this.
Yes.
I'm not enjoying this.
But you should get a yes, please.
What, I have to put yes, please?
[chuckles]
No, bro.
If someone's going to DM you the word
change, they should just
be like, "Here's your guide." Thank you.
Mm.
And then it takes them to a page,
pop in your email address,
and I'll send the
guide to you straight away. What
is this doing as far as like a chatbot
response?
What's the benefit of, yo,
I've just told you I want it
and you've not given it to
me straight away? That's pissed me off.
Mm.
Now I'm here. So
this needs work. This is naff.
Everything below is going so well.
Yeah.
You've got to change your microphone so we
get audio in both ears.
And there's obviously so much
maturation into the role
that we're going to get into and stuff,
but
make it seamless. How many
free guides you giving out a week,
or how many emails you getting a week?
So right now, I have
one email or lead magnet,
where I teach what you need to start
calisthenic as a beginner. And I give them
14 days. So in 14 days,
I give them 14 ways-
Yep
...
on how to start calisthenic as a beginner.
And then I give out a free YouTube
muscle-up
guide where I just go through
techniques
you need to think about,
and just what you need
to think about to master the muscle-up.
And I do the same with the pull-up
and the handstand.
So [sighs]
And I-
I think you're in such a good niche
where you can be a lot more specific with
a
lead magnet.
For me,
it's like how to improve landing page
conversions,
how to get more views on social media.
You can be like,
"Get your fucking first muscle-up, boom.
How to do a three-minute deadhang,
boom." Because these are the outcomes that
people want. So for that lead magnet,
I love the fact it's 14 ways,
14 days to get
better at something.
But I think you should go
outcome-orientated with that, and
just go, "This is what you need. This
is how you get it." [coughs]
Then I think that once people take those
lead magnets, you
just follow up with them,
and the emails you send them
in those follow-up sequences should talk
about
how your clients have overcome problems,
give them some practical takeaways, then
tell them why they should work with you
one-to-one.
You got a good guarantee for your
one-to-one as well?
Yes. I have
money-back guarantee.
Just say to people, like, if you do not-
Because you pay monthly.
Yeah, sweet.
So like you say to someone like, "Look,
hey, you've told me you want
to get strong, you want to feel empowered,
you want to do this, you want to do
this, you want to do this, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
Just to let you know,
if you sign up today
and you don't get that within three
months,
you'll be in a position to get your money
back." Now you tell them that,
you don't say it's an automatic refund,
because in three months' time, they might
not have got their first muscle-up,
but they might be fucking delighted with
the
progress.
But if they're not fucking delighted with
the progress, you're
going to know before three months,
because three weeks in,
they won't have done
anything. And you've just got to say,
"Look, Trevor,
you fat cunt, you're not doing anything.
You're not doing any of the progress.
I'm sending you your money back." You're
going to say, "I don't fucking want
it. I'm sending you your money back.
I don't want it.
I'm Emil Krantz. I don't fucking work with
lazy people. I work with athletes.
I work with people
that want to better themselves,"
or whatever it is.
So yeah, you can have some fun with it.
But ultimately,
I suppose from the top down, if I
was to summarize-
Mm
...
90 minutes,
the content's you're doing really,
really well.
You've done already so much, so great.
Mm.
And you've done it with only talking into
people's one ear, the left side.
So I've sent you the content strategy
document.
It's got your next 25,
30 reels in it Then out of those,
we're going to
see what works well,
and we're going to keep doubling down on
it.
And you're going to go on a mission for
the next year to help
so many people, even myself. I've
got my own gym. I've got the
resources. I can't deadhang,
I can't muscle up.
Have I got the energy to do it? No.
But someone like you could inspire me to
get the spectrum out and just
start going hyper-focus on something like
that.
Then
you're going to talk to me,
you're going to educate me about the false
grip.
You're going to convince me to start doing
my chin-ups differently.
And then as far as that,
we're just going to get as many
email addresses as we can
by putting out really good lead magnets
that help people.
And I don't care if nine out of 10 people
don't buy your shit.
If one out of 10 people on the lead magnet
buy it, you're
going to be quids in, plus you're 22.
Do you live at home?
Yes.
Laughing.
I do.
Laughing. You
get 10 clients,
you're going to be worried about your 10
online clients.
You're going to have issues of where to
hide the cash under the mattress.
You're going to be sleeping badly from
getting a crooked spine from all that cash
under there,
all them euros under the mattress.
So,
that part I'm not concerned about.
This low-ticket community, fuck it off.
Yeah.
It's a headache.
Because
I've recorded a lot of
videos and tutorials,
what do you think I should do with
them?
Give it away as part of your lead magnet.
Put it into your email series.
Give it to people for free.
Right.
[sighs] The issue is,
I
get it, but for the sake of $29,
it might as well be
free. And if you make it free versus $29-
Mm
...
you're going to get 10 times more people
getting it.
If you get 10 times as many people doing
it, you're going to get 10 times as many
people on the high ticket. Plus,
for a
dollar a day,
it might as well be free.
You're just-
Yeah
... setting a massive barrier
that we just don't need.
I don't feel anyway.
And-
Mm-hmm. No
... if there was a bigger audience,
if there was an audience that want--
Get your
phone out for a second.
How many impressions has your Instagram
page had?
And when you go to your homepage, it says
Professional Dashboard.
I don't look at mine because I'm losing
followers sometimes because I don't talk
about-
No
... fitness anymore.
[chuckles] What is it? Monthly recap
or something like that.
I have two million views, new
followers, 8.1 thousand.
Only two million views in the last 30
days.
And three fucking people on your school.
Get rid of it. It's shit house.
It's going.
Yeah.
Make it free if you want.
And that's going to be more valuable.
And that can be your next post.
You can be like, "Hey, guys,
I'm going to cancel
and refund three people on 20 bucks.
I'm making my school free.
I want to make calisthenics available to
everyone.
I'm on a mission to help people do this."
If someone joins your school for free, do
you get their email?
Yes. They have to write their email.
Cool. And do you get to use the email
and add it to your email marketing?
Yeah, probably.
Let's make that bitch free then.
Let's make that bitch free, then next time
I interact with any ManyChat,
you're going to say, "Yo,
thanks for that.
I made a free school community.
If you're interested, click here."
And we're going to siphon people into
there, get
their emails,
and then we're going to hit them about the
high-ticket offer.
And I think it'd be pretty cool,
you're like, "I'm Emil.
I help people with calisthenics.
I've got loads of free resources.
If you want to work with me one-to-one,
it's $250 a month." Bosch.
Yeah. But right now, I have
2,000
emails,
and that's where I got from
one--
Almost
80% is from one video I made, just raw
talking a video on
like...
Yeah, you can take a look at it
if you want.
You got 2,000 email addresses from a
video?
Yeah. Almost.
And how many of them have you closed into
clients?
None.
How many times have you engaged them?
Maybe I have done
three emails a week.
Around three. Yes.
I want that list to be shrunk to 500, and
I want it to be shrunk by pestering the
fuck out of them.
And I want you to be like,
"I've got 10 slots of my online coaching.
I'm going to pester the fuck out of you
guys until you take me up on my services.
It's a three-month guarantee.
The people that are going to join this
program are
going to want to work towards X, Y, Z,
and you've got it here in writing
that if we don't get it,
you get your money back." And then boom,
just keep hitting
them.
And even if they unsubscribe because
they're not interested,
I don't care.
You're telling me there's not-
No
... five clients in that list of 2,000?
I don't believe you.
I don't believe it either.
I don't know.
There's definitely some legs in
that because I need you to shrink
that list.
Do you know why I need you to shrink
that list to 500?
Yeah.
So that you wake up and panic and go,
"Holy fuck, my email list has shrunk
by 75%.
I need to get more leads." Then you take
that
energy to the camera That's where you find
your personality.
Sometimes all you need
is a little sprinkle of desperation in
your content, and
that's what gets you there.
Sometimes you need a little bit of your
bank
overdraft coming into your life.
Sometimes you need to run out of money to
start
working harder.
But yeah, ultimately-
Mm-hmm
... that's
probably your next three months worth of
stuff that needs to be done.
To recap, you're fucking young,
you live at home, you're
Swedish, you're already crushing.
Content could be better,
but just better thought out.
You've already got the skills,
you've already got the opinions.
Face-to-face, you're relatively busy.
Online,
you're already doing all the things right.
From a content perspective, we tweak it,
you can get your content
50% better, with 10% more work. Then,
as far as the
lead magnets,
I think you're in a niche where it should
be easier than ever to get
lead magnets. Check out Harriet Roberts.
I want you to maybe-
Mm
... thieve a couple of ideas from her,
or credit her with things
that you like,
and maybe some things you might disagree
with.
I want you to educate the fuck out of your
audience with the-
Mm
... things that I put in the document.
I want to get rid of the school community
unless we make it free.
The cheapest offer that people
are going to have with Emil Krantz is
$250 a month. And if they can't afford it,
they're going to keep watching content
till they can.
I would like to see a change in the bio.
And there is no way in hell
that these two businesses
take priority over your business.
And through the hierarchy of importance in
the bio, I would say it looks
like you care more about theirs than
yours. Well, let's change that.
If they're unhappy with that,
they can fuck off because they've got
Bitcoin early with Emil Krantz.
I want the username changed, and
I want the bio to be something appealing,
not cheesy, not too boring.
If you're going to put a chatbot,
if someone gives you the chat,
fucking send it in
the first message. None of
that opening message bullshit.
Yeah. [chuckles]
And let's just tidy up the flow.
Every time your email list gets to
2,000,
I want you to spank the daddy out of it
until we fucking
get some clients out of it. And then,
yeah, I want you to just enjoy the process
as much as you can. In two years,
how much roughly are you making a month?
Yeah, not that much, but around
$2,000.
24K a year at 22 is pretty fucking good.
Self-employed. You get time like now on
the early morning. Actually,
it's going to be pretty fucking
early for you.
I've just realized the time difference.
But you're self-employed at 22.
Do you know like, that's fine.
You're living at home, 24K,
running your own shop.
You can get to 100K quicker than anyone
with your friends.
You could be at 100K in two years,
or even three
years, puts you at 25 at 100K a fucking
year.
Your mates have got to go fucking business
executive to sales,
to fucking sales manager,
to junior director.
They're the four years of sucking dick the
whole way.
All of that way up to director level by
the time they're 45 or 50.
You get to bypass that.
So you should be very happy with where
you're at.
Just keep doing what you're doing.
I've sent over that doc.
You've got my email address.
Let's catch up in maybe two months.
Mm.
Sounds good.
Has that helped?
It's very good. Yeah, absolutely.
But what would you say
my bio should look like? What should I
write for the-
Let's do it. All right. Let me just-
For the 14 days-
Okay
... lead magnet.
All right.
Let's change this bio.
Calisthenics changed my life for the
better. Now it's your turn.
That's going to be your title
or something along
that. Calisthenics.
We might go for that like gymnastics
or whatever logo or the
Swedish.
Then,
if you want...
Okay.
If you like my content,
you'll love
my free resources here.
And then a little down arrow. That's it.
Calisthenics changed my life for the
better. Now it's your turn.
If you like-
And then-
... my content,
you'll love my free resources.
Then we're going to put a link-
All right
... to whatever lead magnet you want.
And-
Yes
... so let's put one thing here,
and for any other things,
connect chatbots to what you're doing.
All right?
Let me just show you something quickly.
Let's go to automations.
Let's look at one that crushed recently.
Cool. What did this one? 2,000 clicks.
Look, all I did down here was
chat link.
You know when you're creating a new
automation and it goes opening DM,
fuck that.
I think it looks desperate as fuck.
You're not auto-messaging people
when they follow you either, are you?
Mm-mm.
No.
Good. Looks desperate as shit.
No, no, no, no, no.
I did.
If they-
I did-
If they say-
... and then you told me to not.
[chuckles]
If they say, they comment the word,
just send them the resource.
Just send it to them.
Make it as seamless as possible-
Mm
...
because you're about to be pestering the
fuck out of them with emails.
Let's make the
DMs as
short as possible. Now, hopefully,
some people
will enjoy this chat.
They'll probably head over to your page.
If you're listening to this, support Emil,
and let's look out for some of his
Swedish banter.
I think I've given you enough to run with.
If I give you any more,
you're going to use it as a reason to
not get going. Is there anything else
that you might need help with,
or have I given you enough to move with?
No, it has been very helpful. I
appreciate it a lot.
My pleasure, yeah.
A lot of my questions has been answered,
so I love it.
All right. Well, thank you very much.
I will catch up with you soon anyway.
Thank you.
Mate, that's been great.